What's this?
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
...Footsteps of Spring.
Hey Kobato, who did you give chocolates to?
Who, me?
Yes!
I, um... Let me see, Ms. Sayaka,
Ioryogi-san, Toshihiko and...
No, no. The chocolate for
the person you like best.
Who did you give that to?
What?!
Ah, but of course I like everyone best.
Come on, tell us!
Umm...
Yes?
Sorry to interrupt when you seem
to be having such fun, but...
Please don't get so uptight.
Will you call Sayaka for me?
What are you doing here?
I've come to talk.
For the last time.
Well you can't!
Would you get out of the way?
I will not!
We have a problem...
Kobato.
It's all right. Let him through.
Huh?
It's been awhile, Sayaka.
I ask you again.
Please wait a little while longer.
A little while longer? How much longer is that?
I think I've waited enough.
Why? What has made you change like this?
It's not that I've changed.
This is the true me. How I really am.
Liar.
Why don't you just give it up already?
If you're being stubborn
because of me, you're way off.
As far as I'm concerned, you're a
complete stranger to me now.
What I'm saying is that the fact that I'm
here means you have no way out.
Unless you want to show the kids their
kindergarten being torn down
in front of their very eyes.
Why are you hung up on this place anyway?
You can make a kindergarten anywhere.
Fujimoto!
What the heck are you saying?!
You know better than anyone else!
Fujimoto!
This kindergarten is not just a box!
Ms. Sayaka succeeded this from
her father after he died!
It is very important to her!
There can be no alternative!
If it's not just a box, then what exactly
is it that you're trying to protect?
Is this building more important
than the children?
If putting these children into danger means
nothing to you, then have it your way.
If that's the case though, you're
defeating your own purpose.
Why you...
No, don't!
Go ahead and make the first move.
That might settle things more quickly.
I understand.
I'll close down the kindergarten.
Ms. Sayaka?
But please wait until graduation.
What are you up to now, Dobato?
Hey.
Come on.
Those sheets were just dried and
now you're getting them wet again.
I'm sorry.
Darn. You're just giving me
more work to do again.
I'm really sorry!
I'm going over to Mr. Okiura's place.
What do you expect to get done there?
I'm going to ask him again,
not to shut down Yomogi Kindergarten.
You going there is just going to make things
more complicated than they already are.
But unless we do something...
Anyway, don't go there!
Hey.
You're...
Why did he suddenly show up?
What do you plan to do, once you find that out?
What you're doing is intimidation.
We could report you to the
police if we wanted to.
Huh? If you could do that you'd
have done so long ago.
Besides...
The teacher's decided to shut
down the place, right?
You'd be wise to stop complaining
and get out of there.
I'm not giving up. I'm going
to protect that kindergarten.
How?
You're such a fool. You don't know anything.
Wait a minute!
We're not finished talking.
You think you're being cool by standing up to
us like that saying it's for everyone's sake,
but you know what?
You're just running around in circles.
You know, it's the boss that had his
eye on that kindergarten first.
The boss?
Okiura's father.
The money that the kindergarten owes.
Well, it was Okiura's father that pulled strings
so that the previous principal
would have to pay that back.
No way. That can't be!
Ms. Sayaka's father was stuck trying
desperately to raise money,
something he wasn't used to, and
that anxiety lead to his death.
Okiura knew that. Putting himself at his father's
mercy still makes him just as guilty!
That's why I'm telling you, you don't understand!
Do you know what could happen if the
boss got serious and took action?
So that's why Mr. Okiura came over on his
own, saying he'd take care of things.
I think...
I think Mr. Okiura is taking
on the role of the bad guy
in order to protect the
kindergarten from the boss.
Or should I say, in order to
protect the woman he loves.
Stop talking nonsense!
How you take it is up to you.
But let me say just this.
Kobato, was it?
I owe her one.
So I don't want to see her get mixed
up in this and get herself hurt.
Just do as Mr. Okiura says.
Yomogi Kindergarten
Graduation
...top of the hill
Yomogi Kindergarten
Graduation
We can see everything, what a thrill
Let's go look, let's go look
Let's find wonderful things today
Congratulations on Your Graduation
Toshihiko
Marina Yoshio
Let's find wonderful things today
The other kindergartens are all filled up.
I'm on a waiting list, too.
I'm so sorry that things had to end up this way.
Bon appetite!
Wh-What's this?
Please join us for dinner if you'd like.
If we all eat together,
nobody will be lonely, right?
Chise!
U-Um... I'm very thankful, but...
I can't eat anything right now.
What?
I understand. I guess it's difficult to get in the
mood to have dinner with others right now.
Oh no, um...
I truly appreciate your thoughts.
Father.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't able to protect the kindergarten.
But you know, Father, even after all this, there's
still a part of me that wants to believe that man.
You must think I'm pretty silly.
Ms. Chitose, I saw Mr. Okiura in
front of the kindergarten today.
What?
To me, he seemed very lonely.
Is that right?
He's the one that's telling us
at the kindergarten to leave.
Perhaps he's still in love with Sayaka.
I think Sayaka feels the same way about him too.
Then why is Mr. Okiura doing things
to make Ms. Sayaka sad?
Sometimes it's because you love each other,
because you care for each other that
misunderstandings occur.
Oh! It's him!
Maybe if I follow him,
he'll lead me to Mr. Okiura.
Hey...
Excuse me!
Huh?
Let me see him, please! Let me see Mr. Okiura!
Young lady, you'd be better
off staying out of this.
Please!
Meeting him won't do you any good. Go home.
Please reconsider!
Send her back.
I don't think she's the type that will
leave just because she's told to.
Then leave her be.
She's still there.
Mr. Okiura?
Why is everyone so hung up
on one little kindergarten?
Ioryogi-san, do you feel cold?
Of course I'm cold.
If you've figured that out, why don't you find an
umbrella somewhere or find shelter at least?
But, when Mr. Okiura eventually
looks out of that window,
he won't notice me unless
I'm standing right here.
Doing this isn't going to make him come out.
He will come out at some point.
If not today, then tomorrow.
If not tomorrow, the next day.
How long do you plan to wait here?
I'll wait here as long as it takes,
until he comes out.
How long are you going to continue this?
Mr. Okiura!
Um...
I have nothing to discuss with you.
The kindergarten will be torn down and the
land will be used to pay back the loans.
Then everything's settled.
But I...
I came here to ask you about something else.
Mr. Okiura, I want to ask
about your true feelings.
Like I said, the kindergarten will be...
No, not that!
You're becoming a nuisance.
Ms. Chitose told me.
She said that you still... you still love Ms.
Sayaka, and she still loves you, too.
Is that what you came here to say?
Mr. Okiura!
If you care so much about Ms. Sayaka, why
do you do things to hurt her like that?!
We were all happy there.
Ms. Sayaka, me, Fujimoto, all the children at
Yomogi Kindergarten, we all liked it there.
That's why.
That's why Ms. Sayaka tried so
hard to protect it, I'm sure!
But you... you took Yomogi Kindergarten
away from her. You made her sad.
After what you've done, I cannot
think of you as a good man.
But even if you aren't a good man, if you
are an important person to Ms. Sayaka,
then things cannot remain like this!
Please tell me!
Basically, we were from different worlds.
My father was too powerful for me.
This is the only way I know how to protect her.
So you don't hate Ms. Sayaka.
You truly care about her.
Huh? Hey!
Ms. Sayaka.
Fujimoto...
I can't seem to get any sleep. You too?
Ms. Sayaka.
That guy. He was being the bad guy,
in order to protect you.
What?
Fujimoto, what are you talking about?
Okiura.
No... b-but...
Even so, I'm not about to forgive him.
What are you saying?!
Unless you forgive him, he's got
no choice but to disappear!
Are you okay with that?!
I... I really want you to be happy.
He's the only one that can save you.
So, Ms. Sayaka, you have to be with him.
But...
Oh good, you've come to.
Ms. Sayaka?
I hear you were standing out in
the rain for the longest time.
Looking back, I'm the one that's
always been protected.
By you, Kobato, by Fujimoto...
...and by him.
Where's Mr. Okiura?!
He just left.
Are you going to leave things the way they are?!
Huh?
Ms. Sayaka.
If even now, you truly care for Mr. Okiura...
Then run after him and give him a hug!
Hurry!
This is not good.
Don't you forget what you're wishing for.
Your smiling face falls
Between the border of things I've lost
And things I have gained
You're just out of arm's reach
And I can't fly to cover the distance
I just want to make you smile,
So why did I have to get stuck with
Such terribly useless wings?
I'll smile when I'm with you,
Since that's all I can do
I want to wrap my wings around you
To keep you warm
I now realize that's what these wings are for
As I give you a heartfelt smile
Next episode
...Day to Say Goodbye.
As I give you a heartfelt smile
Next episode
...Day to Say Goodbye.